(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-15T12:34:05.217603",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
さあ、始まりました！
Now, it has begun!
4周年だよ！宝鐘マリン アホイホイ！昭和歌謡祭
It's the 4th anniversary! Houshou Marine Ahoy Ahoy! Showa Kayou Festival
懐かしの名曲をホロライブが誇るスターが大熱唱
Hololive's proudest stars passionately sing nostalgic masterpieces!
大海原を夢見て資金稼ぎに奔走する宝鐘海賊団船長 宝鐘マリン
Houshou Marine, captain of the Houshou Pirates, striving to earn funds while dreaming of the open sea.
話し出すと止まらないオタク族の猫娘 白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki, the otaku cat-girl who never stops talking once she starts.
どこからともなく現れた神出鬼没の狼少女 大神ミオ
Ookami Mio, the elusive wolf girl who appeared out of nowhere.
歌も若さも楽しめる歌謡祭だもの たっぷり一時間
A one-hour Kayou festival full of youthful songs and fun!
カラーでお送りいたします
Presented in color!
あなたが好きだから それでいいのよ
Because I love you, that's fine by me
たとえ一緒に 街を歩けなくても
Even if we can't walk together through the streets
この部屋にいつも 帰ってくれたら
As long as you always return to this room
わたしは 待つ身の女でいいの
I don't mind being the woman who waits
尽くして 泣き濡れて そして愛されて
Devoting myself, soaked in tears, and then being loved
時がふたりを 離さぬように
So that time won't tear us apart
見つめて 寄りそって そしてだきしめて
Gazing, drawing close, and then holding me tight
このまま あなたの胸で暮らしたい
I want to live right here in your arms
めぐり逢い 少しだけ 遅いだけなの
Our meeting was just a little too late
何も言わずいてね わかっているわ
Don't say anything, just be there, I understand
心だけせめて 残してくれたら
If you can leave at least your heart behind
わたしは 見送る女でいいの
I don't mind being the woman who sees you off
尽くして 泣き濡れて そして愛されて
Devoting myself, soaked in tears, and then being loved
明日がふたりを こわさぬように
So that tomorrow won't destroy the two of us
離れて 恋しくて そして会いたくて
Apart, longing for you, and wanting to see you
このまま あなたの胸で眠りたい
I want to sleep right here in your arms
尽くして 泣き濡れて そして愛されて
Devoting myself, soaked in tears, and then being loved
明日がふたりを こわさぬように
So that tomorrow won't destroy the two of us
離れて 恋しくて そして会いたくて
Apart, longing for you, and wanting to see you
このまま あなたの胸で暮らしたい
I want to live right here in your arms
さあ、始まってきました、宝鐘マリン4周年昭和歌謡祭！
Now then, the Houshou Marine 4th Anniversary Showa Kayou Festival has begun!
司会の白上フブキと
Hosted by Shirakami Fubuki
大神ミオです。よろしくお願いします！
and Ookami Mio. Nice to meet you!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
いや、今年も呼んでいただけましたね。
Well, you invited us again this year.
ええ、そうですね。
Yeah, that's right.
まさか、去年から引き続き呼んでいただけると思いませんでしたね。
I didn't expect you to keep inviting us since last year.
よかったなと思っております。
I'm glad to hear that.
お仕事ありがとうございます。
Thank you for your hard work.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
いや、先ほどの愛人ですけども、そうですね。宝鐘マリンさんの愛人でした。
Now, about that "mistress" earlier... That's right, it was Houshou Marine's mistress.
はい。
Yes.
あれなんですかね。2番目の女でもいいということなんですかね。
What's that about? Does it mean being the second woman is fine too?
あ、そうなんですね。
Ah, is that so?
宝鐘マリンは2番目。
Houshou Marine is the second one.
あ、でも普通は1番目になりたいんじゃないかなって思うんですけどね。
Ah, but usually wouldn't you want to be the first?
あ、大神さんはそうですか？
Ah, Ookami-san, is that you?
いや、まあ、当たり前だとは思いますけれども。
Well, I suppose that goes without saying.
あ、そうですか。
I see.
ちなみに私は2番目でもいいかなと。
By the way, I wouldn't mind being second.
え？そうなんですか？
Eh? Is that so?
と思っております。
That's what I think.
じゃ、マリンさんと一緒ってことですね。
Then that means being together with Marine-san.
あ、そうですね。
Ah, right.
2番目でも愛してくれるならいいかもしれないんですね。
If they love me even as the second, maybe that's fine.
愛には飢えてはいるんです。
I am starving for love.
なんの話してるんですか一体。愛の話ではないんですか？
What on earth are you talking about? Isn't it a talk about love?
あー、まあまあ、そうですね。愛の話だと思います。
Ah, well, that's right. I think it's a talk about love.
そうですね。はい。
That's right. Yes.
みおさんは愛人はいらっしゃいますか？
Mio-san, do you have a mistress?
いるわけないじゃないですか！
As if I would have one!
私一筋ということですか？
Eh, so you're devoted only to me?
え？え？
Eh? Eh?
え、突然そんな。われわれの関係は一体？
Eh, suddenly like that. What on earth is our relationship?
てっきりおかゆさんと最近仲がいいと聞きましたけども。
I heard you've been getting close with Okayu-san recently.
私の話はいいじゃないですか。進行しましょう。
Ah, never mind my talk. Let's proceed.
進行しましょう。
Let's proceed.
はいはい。ということで始まっていきましたけども。
Right, right. With that, we've started.
本日もね、たくさんの昭和の曲が揃っているということで楽しみですね。
Today as well, there are lots of Showa songs lined up, so I'm looking forward to it.
本当楽しみでございますね。
I'm really looking forward to it.
じゃあ、早速次に行きましょうか。
Well then, let's move on to the next one right away.
はい。
Yes.
それでは次の曲、どうぞ！
Well then, the next song, here it is!
突然のキスや 熱いまなざしで
With a sudden kiss and a passionate gaze,
恋のプログラムを 狂わせないでね
Do not mess up the love program.
出逢いと別れ 上手に打ち込んで
Handling encounters and farewells skillfully,
時間がくれば 終わる
When the time comes, it ends.
Don't hurry !
Don't hurry!
愛に傷ついた あの日からずっと
Ever since that day when my heart was hurt by love,
昼と夜が逆の 暮らしを続けて
I've been living with my days and nights reversed,
はやりのDiscoで 踊り明かすうちに
Dancing the night away at a trendy disco,
おぼえた魔術なのよ
It's a magic I learned.
I'm sorry !
I'm sorry!
私のことを決して 本気で愛さないで
Never truly fall in love with me,
恋なんてただのゲーム 楽しめばそれでいいの
Love is just a game, just enjoy it and that's fine.
閉ざした心を飾る
Adorning my closed heart,
派手なドレスも靴も 孤独な友達
Showy dresses, shoes, and lonely friends.
私を誘う人は 皮肉なものね いつも
The men who invite me are always ironic,
彼に似てるわ なぜか 思い出と重なり合う
Resembling him for some reason, overlapping with memories,
グラスを落として急に
Dropping my glass and suddenly...
涙ぐんでもわけは
Even if I tear up, don't ask why...
尋ねないでね
...don't ask me why.
夜明けの高速で眠りにつくころ
When I fall asleep by the highway at dawn,
ハロゲンライトだけ妖しく輝く
only halogen lights are mysteriously shining.
氷のように冷たい女だと
Murmuring that I'm an icy cold woman,
ささやく声がしても
even if someone whispers...
Don't worry!
I'm just playing games
I know that's plastic love
Dance to the plastic beat
Another morning comes
I'm just playing games
I know that's plastic love
Dance to the plastic beat
Another morning comes
子供たちが空に向かい 両手をひろげ
Children are spreading their arms towards the sky,
鳥や雲や夢までも つかもうとしている
trying to grab birds, clouds, and even dreams.
その姿は きのうまでの何も知らない私
Recalling the clueless person I was until yesterday,
あなたに この指が届くと信じていた
believing my fingers would reach you.
空と大地が 触れ合う彼方
The faraway place where the sky and land meet,
過去からの旅人を 呼んでいる道
the path summoning travelers from the past.
あなたにとって私 ただの通りすがり
To you, I'm just a mere passerby,
ちょっとふり向いてみただけの異邦人
a foreigner you just glanced at as you walked past.
市場へ行く人の波に 身体を預け
Giving myself up to the tide of people heading to the market,
石だたみの街角を ゆらゆらとさまよう
wandering around the cobblestone street corners.
祈りの声 ひずめの音 歌うようなざわめき
A chorus of prayer, hoofbeats, and street noise resembling a song,
私を置きざりに 過ぎてゆく白い朝
a hazy morning passes by and leaves me behind.
時間旅行が 心の傷を
A time travel heals the wounds of my heart,
なぜかしら埋めてゆく 不思議な道
for some reason, filling them on this strange path.
サヨナラだけの手紙 迷い続けて書き
Writing a letter with just a goodbye after much hesitation.
サヨナラだけの手紙迷い続けて書き
I wrote a letter with only the word "goodbye", lost in hesitation,
あとは哀しみをもて余す異邦人
and now I'm left with only sorrow to hold on to, a stranger.
プラスティックラブ 紫咲シオン 宝鐘マリン
Plastic Love by Shion Murasaki and Houshou Marine,
異邦人 あずき 宝鐘マリンの2曲をお送りいたしました
and Ihoujin by AZKi and Houshou Marine.
いや、いい曲でしたね。
Man, that was a great song.
うん、素晴らしいですねー。
Yeah, it was wonderful.
うち、宇宙人の方結構うまくいったと思うんですけど、どうでしたか？
I think "Uchuujin" went pretty well, how was it?
あ、もしかして曲の前の... そうです。
Ah, you mean before the song... That's right.
そうですね、もう一回聴いてみましょうか。いや、あの結構です。
Is that so? Shall we listen to it again? No, thanks.
曲の話しましょうね。はい。
Let's talk about the songs. Right.
いや、プラスティックラブよかったですね。
Plastic Love was really good.
宝鐘マリンさんが紫咲シオンさんにちょっとこう振り回されるみたいな感じで、シオンさんの魔性の女ぶりを歌いたかったみたいですよ。
It seemed like Marine was being pushed around by Shion, wanting to sing about her femme fatale charm.
なるほど。じゃあ宝鐘マリンさんの魔性の女ぶりは、紫咲シオンさんから実は来ているという。
I see. So Marine's vibe actually comes from Shion.
それはまたちょっと違うかなと思いますけど。
I think that's a bit different.
お手本にしてると聞いたんですけど、違ったんですね。
I heard you were using her as a role model, guess not.
あずきさんもね、すごい綺麗な歌声なので。異邦人を聴いてみたいということで。
AZKi has a wonderful voice, so she wanted to sing Ihoujin.
宇宙人だったんでしょうか、あずきさんは。
Was AZKi an alien too?
あずきさんは違ったんじゃないですか。
I don't think AZKi was.
あ、違うんですか。もっともで綺麗な歌声でしたね。
Oh, really? Well, either way it was a beautiful song.
はい、じゃあ次の曲行きましょうか。
Okay, shall we move on to the next song?
それでは次の曲、どうぞ。
Now then, please enjoy the next song.
天城越え
Amagigoe
隠しきれない 移り香が いつしかあなたに 浸みついた
The changing face that cannot be hidden before you know it, it clings to you
誰かに盗られる くらいなら
if it's to the point of being taken by someone else
あなたを殺して いいですか
is it okay to kill you?
寝乱れて 隠れ宿
Scattered in sleep, hidden shelter
九十九折り 浄蓮の滝
Folded up, the waterfall of passion
舞い上がり 揺れ堕ちる 肩のむこうに あなた
Rising and falling, beyond the swaying shoulders, you...
山が燃える
The mountain burns
何があっても もういいの くらくら燃える 火をくぐり あなたと越えたい
No matter what happens, it's fine now, passing through the burning fire, wanting to cross over with you,
天城越え
Beyond Amagi
口を開けば 別れると
If I open my mouth, we'll part ways
刺さったまんまの 割れ硝子
The broken glass that stays stuck
ふたりで居たって 寒いけど
Even if we're together, it's cold
嘘でも抱かれりゃ あたたかい
But if it's a lie, being held is warm
わさび沢 隠れ径
Hidden path of wasabi zawa
小夜時雨 寒天橋
Evening rain, kanten bridge
恨んでも 恨んでも 躯うらはら あなた
Resentful, resentful, the body is in conflict, you...
山が燃える
The mountain burns
戻れなくてもいいの
Even if there's no turning back,
くらくら燃える地を這って
crawling on the dizzying, burning earth...
...crawling on the dizzying, burning earth.
あなたと越えたい
I want to cross over with you,
天城越え
beyond Amagi.
走り水 迷い恋
Running water, straying love,
風の群れ 天城隧道
a flock of wind, Amagi Tunnel.
恨んでも 恨んでも 身体うらはら あなた
Resenting and resenting, my body betrays me, my love...
山が燃える
The mountain burns.
戻れなくてもいいの
Even if there's no turning back,
くらくら燃える地を這って
crawling on the dizzying, burning earth.
あなたと越えたい
I want to cross over with you,
天城越え
beyond Amagi.
みよ、俺は、君となら毎日アスファルトにタイヤを切り付けたっていいと思ってんだけど。
Miyo, if it were with you, I'd be fine tearing up asphalt with tires every single day.
返しやすいセリフにしろって言っただろ！返しやすくなかったか？
I told you to make it an easy line to respond to! Wasn't it easy to respond?
というわけで、お次の曲ですね。はい、そうですね。はい。
With that said, the next song. Yes, that's right. Yes.
ゲットワイルドなんですけども。いいですか？タイヤを切り付けていくのは。
It's "Get Wild". Is that okay? Slicing up the tires as we go.
別に、あの切り付けるのはいいんですけど、あ、えーそれでは聴いてください。「Get Wild」
Well, slicing them up is fine, but ah... well then, please listen. "Get Wild".
アスファルト タイヤを切りつけながら
While cutting the asphalt tires,
暗闇走り抜ける
running through the darkness.
チープなスリルに身をまかせても 明日にびえていたよ
Even when surrendering to cheap thrills, I was terrified of tomorrow.
It's your pain or my pain or somebody's pain
誰かのために生きられるなら
If we can live for someone else,
It's your dream or my dream or somebody's dream
何もこわくはない
there is nothing to fear.
Get wild and tough ひとりでは解けない愛のパズルを抱いて
Get wild and tough, embracing the unsolvable puzzle of love alone,
Get wild and tough この街でやさしさに甘えていたくはない
Get wild and tough, I don't want to rely on tenderness in this town.
Get chance and luck 君だけが守れるものがどこかにあるさ
Get chance and luck, somewhere there is something only you can protect.
Get chance and luck ひとりでも傷ついた夢をとりもどすよ
Get chance and luck, I'll reclaim the wounded dream even if I'm alone.
クルマのライトにkissを投げては
Throwing a kiss at car headlights,
車道で踊るあの娘
that girl dancing on the road.
冷たい夜空をステージにして 哀しくおどけていたね
Making the cold night sky her stage, she clowned around sorrowfully.
It's your pain or my pain or somebody's pain
誰かのために愛せるのなら
If we can love for someone else,
It's your dream or my dream or somebody's dream
きっと強くなれる
we can surely become stronger.
Get wild and tough ひとりでは消せない痛み心に抱いて
Get wild and tough, holding an unquenchable pain in our hearts,
Get wild and tough この街で自由をもてあましたくはない
Get wild and tough, I don't want to squander freedom in this town.
Get chance and luck 君だけが守れるものをみつけだしたら
Get chance and luck, once you find something only you can protect,
Get chance and luck ひとりでも傷ついた夢をとりもどすよ
Get chance and luck, I'll reclaim the wounded dream even if I'm alone.
Get wild and tough ひとりでは
解けない愛のパズルを抱いて
Get wild and tough, embracing
the love puzzle that can't be solved alone
Get wild and tough この街で
やさしさに甘えていたくはない
Get wild and tough, I don't want
to rely on kindness in this town
Get chance and luck 君だけに
守れるものがどこかにあるさ
Get chance and luck, there is somewhere
something only you can protect
Get chance and luck ひとりでも
傷ついた夢をとりもどすよ
Get chance and luck, I'll recover
my hurt dream even alone
甘口声、甘え果て方、宝鐘マリン。
Sweet voice, the ultimate spoiled style, Houshou Marine.
Get Wildと、ハコス・ベールズ、宝鐘マリンでお送りいたしました。
Brought to you by Houshou Marine with "Get Wild" and Hakos Baelz!
いいですね。はい。
That was great. Yes.
素晴らしい2曲でございました。かっこよかったですね。
It was two wonderful songs. So cool, right?
かっこよかったですね。はい。
So cool. Yes.
いや、あの、最近あの宝鐘マリンさんは、ハコスさんと仲良くなったので、歌ってみたということで。
Lately, Houshou Marine has become good friends with Hakos, so they sang this together.
英語ほぼ押し付けでしたけどね。あ、そうですね。
Even though it was basically forcing English on her. Well, yes.
あ、そういえばハコス・ベールズさんのさっきのなんか情報握ってるみたいなのはいったい何だったんでしょうか?
Oh, by the way, what was that about Hakos Baelz holding some info earlier?
かなマリンは、あの、甘声どころかもう一層を超えてしまったという情報でございました。
Kanamarine crossed even the sweet voice tier... she crossed it into another level.
夜を共にしてしまったそうです。
Apparently, they spent the night together.
それはちょっとあの、スキャンダルというやつなんじゃ…。甘え声ですね。
Is that some kind of scandal...? Pampered voices.
それでは次の曲まいりましょうか。はい。それでは次の曲、どうぞどうぞ!
Now let's move on to the next song. Yes. Then, the next song, go ahead!
ああ 私の恋は南の風に乗って走るわ
Ah, my love rides on the southern wind
ああ 青い風切って走れ あの島へ
Ah, blue wind, run to that island
あなたと逢うたびに
Every time I meet you,
すべてを忘れてしまうの
I forget everything
はしゃいだ私は Little Girl
I'm excited, I'm a little girl,
熱い胸きこえるでしょう
can you hear my hot heart?
素肌にキラキラ珊瑚礁
Coral reefs shining on my skin,
二人きりで流されてもいいの
even if we're swept away alone
あなたが好き!
I love you!
ああ 私の恋は南の風に乗って走るわ
Ah, my love rides on the southern wind
ああ 青い風切って走れ あの島へ
Ah, blue wind, run to that island
涙がこぼれるの
Tears spill,
やさしい目をして見ないで
don't look at me with gentle eyes
うつ向き加減の Little Rose
Little rose in a sullen mood,
花びら 触れて欲しいの
I want the petals to touch
渚は恋の モスグリーン
The shore is a moss green of love,
二人の頬が近づいてゆくのよ
our cheeks are getting closer
あなたが好き！
I love you!
ああ 私の恋は南の風に乗って走るわ
Ah, my love rides on the southern wind,
ああ 青い風切って走れ あの島へ
Ah, blue wind, run to that island.
あなたと逢うたびに
Every time I meet you,
すべてを忘れてしまうの
I forget everything...
はしゃぎすぎた私は Little Girl
I was a little too excited, a little girl.
熱い胸騒ぎするでしょう
Can you feel my racing heart?
素肌にキラキラ珊瑚礁
Coral reefs shining on my skin.
二人きりで流されてもいいの あなたが好き
Even if we drift away alone, I love you.
ああ 私の恋は南の風に乗って走るわ
Ah, my love rides on the southern wind,
ああ 青い風切って走れ あの島へ
Ah, blue wind, run to that island.
リズムよく二人のおかげ
With good rhythm, thanks to both of us!
今 友情、愛情いろんなものが混ざり合った拳が二人の歩幅を突き抜けていく
Now fists mixing friendship, affection, and more drive our stride forward!
気づいちゃったでしょ それは 縦横無尽
You noticed, didn't you? It's limitless!
立ち上がるコボ そして その拳を…
Kobo stands up, and that fist...
それでは聴いてください フレンズです
Now then, please listen. It's "Friends"!
口づけを かわした日は
When your lips touched mine,
ママの顔さえも 見れなかった
I couldn't even look at my mom's face.
ポケットの コインあつめて
Gathering the coins in my pocket,
ひとつずつ 夢をかぞえたね
We counted our dreams one by one.
ほら あれは2人の かくれが
Look, that was our hiding place.
ひみつのメモリー oh
Our secret memory, oh
どこでこわれたの oh フレンズ
Where did it break, oh friends?
うつむく日は 見つめあって
Days when we cast our eyes down, looking at each other,
指をつないだら oh フレンズ
When we held hands, oh friends,
時がとまる気がした
I felt time stand still.
ねえ 君は覚えている
Hey, do you remember
夕映えによくにあうあの曲
That song that fits the sunset so well?
だまりこむ君がいつも
Even though you were always quiet and sad,
悲しくて 口づさんだのに
Humming it quietly to yourself...
今 時は流れて セピアに染まるメロディー oh
Now time flows on, a melody dyed in sepia, oh
2度とどれない oh フレンズ
Can never go back, oh friends.
他人よりも 遠く見えて
Looking more distant than strangers,
いつも走ってた oh フレンズ
Always running, oh friends.
あの瞳が いとおしい
Those eyes are so dear.
どこでこわれたの oh フレンズ
Where did it break, oh friends?
うつむく日は 見つめあって
Days when we cast our eyes down, looking at each other,
指をつないだら oh フレンズ
When we held hands, oh friends,
時がとまる気がした
I felt time stand still.
2度とどれない oh フレンズ
Can never go back, oh friends.
他人よりも 遠く見えて
Looking more distant than strangers,
いつも走ってた oh フレンズ
Always running, oh friends.
あの瞳が いとおしい
Those eyes are so dear.
葵さんごしょ みなとあくあ ほうしょうまりん
"Aoi Sangoshou" by Minato Aqua and Houshou Marine,
フレンズ、こぼかなえる、ほうしょうまりんの2曲をお送りいたしました。
and "Friends" by Kobo Kanaeru and Houshou Marine.
いや、いいですね。なぎさんの親子でしたね。
Right, that's nice. It was Nagi-san's parent-child song.
いや、そうですね。
Yeah, that's right.
えー、マリンさんは、えー、あくあさんとはこう、海つながりということで、去年から海にまつわる歌を…。
Um, Marine-san, since you and Aqua-san are connected by the sea, since last year you've been selecting sea-related songs...
選曲されてますね。はい。いやいい親子の曲でございました。
You've been selecting them, right? Yes. Yeah, it was a great parent-child song.
はい。はい。
Yes. Yes.
え、フレンズはですね、え、こぼさんとは、え、親友だと思っていると。思っている。
And for "Friends", um, with Kobo-san, um, you think of her as a close friend. You think so.
はい。
Yes.
実は違うんですか?ただ、え、今回はちょっと友情崩壊する曲をなぜか選曲してしまって…。
Is it actually different? But, um, this time you somehow chose a song about friendship falling apart...
混ぜてましたね、バカ。はい。
You mixed it in, you idiot. Yes.
それはあの、そうですね、白上さんの解釈では…。
That is, um, well, according to Shirakami-san's interpretation...
あ、私の解釈ですけど。はい。
Ah, that's my interpretation. Yes.
すごい熱い青春を感じましたね。あー、白上さんの解釈ではっていうことですね。
I felt a very passionate youth. Ah, so that's Shirakami-san's interpretation.
そうですね、やはり拳しか勝たんということですね。拳しか勝たん。実際そうなのかどうかはわからないですけど。はい。
That's right, after all, only fists can win. Only fists. Whether that's actually true or not, I don't know, but. Yes.
というわけで、次の曲まいりましょう。
With that, let's move on to the next song.
それでは次の曲、どうぞ！
Now then, the next song, here we go!
おいで ファンタジー 好きさ ミステリー
Coming out of fantasy, a lovely mystery
君の若さ 隠さないで
Don't hide your youth
不思議したくて 冒険したくて
I want thrills, I want adventure
誰もみんな ウズウズしてる
Everyone is itching for one
大人のフリして あきらめちゃ
If you pretend to be adult and give up
奇跡の謎など 解けないよ
Things like miracles can't be solved
もっとワイルドに もっとたくましく
You have to try to live wilder, stronger
生きてごらん
Live your life
ロマンティックあげるよ
I'll give you romance
ホントの勇気 見せてくれたら
If you show your true courage
ロマンティックあげるよ
I'll give you romance
ときめく胸に
For your throbbing heart
キラキラ光った 夢をあげるよ
I'll give you a sparkly, shiny dream!
いつか ワンダフル きっと ビューティフル
Someday it'll be wonderful, I'm sure it'll be beautiful
人のジャングル 迷い込んで
Getting lost in a jungle of people
スリルしたくて 幸せしたくて
I want thrills, I want happiness
何故か みんな ソワソワしてる
Somehow, everyone is restless
思ったとおりに 叫ばなきゃ
If you don't shout as loud as you want
願いは空まで 届かない
Your wishes can't reach the sky
もっとセクシーに もっと美しく
You have to try to live sexier, more beautiful
生きてごらん
Live your life
ロマンティックあげるよ
I'll give you romance
ホントの涙 見せてくれたら
If you show your true tears
ロマンティックあげるよ
I'll give you romance
淋しい心 優しく包んで 愛をあげるよ
To wrap around your lonely heart, I'll give you love!
ロマンティックあげるよ
I'll give you romance
ホントの勇気 見せてくれたら
If you show your true courage
ロマンティックあげるよ
I'll give you romance
ときめく胸に
For your throbbing heart
キラキラ光った 夢をあげるよ
I'll give you a sparkly, shiny dream!
ロマンティックあげるよ
I'll give you romance
I'll give you romance.
兎田ぺこら、不知火フレア、白銀ノエル、宝鐘マリンの4名でお送りいたしました。
Brought to you by Usada Pekora, Shiranui Flare, Shirogane Noel, and Houshou Marine.
いやあ、酸基来ましたね！
Man, that really hit the spot!
そうですね。
Indeed.
素晴らしかったですね、可愛かったですね。
It was wonderful, wasn't it? So cute.
はい。
Yes.
で、で、この曲はですね、え、冒頭に「おいでファンタジー」という歌詞がありまして、え、その歌詞に倣って、え、来たぞファンタジーということで。
Now, this song, um, starts with the lyrics "Come on, fantasy," so following those lyrics, we went with "Fantasy is here."
ああ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
はい、アンチュクレですね。
Yes, a subtle play on words.
あ。
Ah.
はい、ほろライブファンタジーなので、ああ、そうですね、そういえばそうでした。
Right, Hololive Fantasy, so—ah, that's right, it was.
はい、ちょっと忘れておりましたね、ファンタジー。そのことないですよ、忘れてないです、はい。私は忘れておりました、大変失礼いたしました。はい。
Yeah, we almost forgot about Fantasy. No way, I didn't forget, yep. I had forgotten, my sincere apologies. Yep.
みおさん最近ロマンティック感じたことありますか？
Mio-san, have you felt romantic lately?
ロマンティック感じるのなかなか難しいですね。ないですか？
Feeling romantic is pretty difficult. How about you?
逆にありますか？ありますか、何か？
Conversely, do you? Is there anything?
やっぱりありますね。やっぱりあの公式から供給されるやっぱり推しの要素をいただくとやはりね、胸がキュンとしてね、ロマンティックを感じますね。
Of course there is. When we get official content of our oshi, it makes our hearts go doki-doki, and we feel the romance.
テーテーというやつですね。
Ah, that "teetee" feeling.
あ、そうですね。ありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。拝み散らかしますね。はい。
Yes, exactly. Thank you very much. I just worship them. Yep.
というわけで、え、次なんですけれども、なんと新曲もあるらしいです。この昭和の時代に新曲。
So, um, for the next part, apparently there's a brand new song! A new song in this Showa era.
あ、そうなんです。
Oh, that's right.
昭和ソングなんでしょうか、果たして。ちょっと楽しみですね。
I wonder if it's a Showa song. I'm looking forward to it.
楽しみですね。
Me too.
はい。それでは次の曲、まいりましょう。
Well then, let's move on to the next song.
どうぞ。
Here it is.
To you... yes my love to you
銃口たちに付き合えないから
I can't keep up with the gun barrels
グルグルと回るおもちゃは涙のマリナイ
Spinning toys are Marina's tears...
このあとプレミア公開
[Text: Premiere coming up next]
To you... yes my love to you
私は私 貴方は貴方と
I am who I am, and you are who you are,
昨夜言ってた そんな気もするわ
I feel like you told me last night.
グレイのジャケットに 見覚えがあるコーヒーのしみ
There's a familiar coffee stain on your grey jacket.
相変わらずなのね ショーウィンドウに二人映れば
You haven't changed at all as we reflect in the shop window.
stay with me... 真夜中のドアをたたく
Stay with me... knocking on midnight's door,
帰らないとと泣いた
crying for you not to go home.
あの季節が今目の前
That season is right before my eyes now.
stay with me... 口ぐせを言いながら
Stay with me... uttering my favorite phrase,
二人の瞬間を抱いて
embracing the moments we shared together,
まだ忘れず大事にしていた
still remembering and cherishing them.
恋と愛とは 違うものだよと
Love and romance are different things,
昨夜言われた そんな気もするわ
I feel like you told me last night.
二度目の冬が来て 離れていった貴方の心
When the second winter came, your heart drifted away.
振り返ればいつも そこに貴方を感じていたの
Looking back, I always felt you right there.
stay with me...
真夜中のドアをたたき
Knocking on midnight's door,
心に穴があいた
A hole opened up in my heart.
あの季節が 今目の前
That season is right before my eyes now.
stay with me... 淋しさまぎらわして
Stay with me... distracting myself from the loneliness,
置いたレコードの針
I put the needle on the record
同じメロディ繰り返していた......
and repeated the same melody over and over......
stay with me...
真夜中のドアをたたき
Knocking on midnight's door,
帰れないと泣いた
crying because I couldn't go home.
あの季節が 今目の前
That season is right before my eyes now.
stay with me... 口ぐせを言いながら
Stay with me... while saying our favorite phrases,
二人の時間を抱いて
embracing the moments we shared together,
まだ忘れず暖めてた
and still keeping them warm without forgetting.
stay with me... 真夜中のドアをたたき
Stay with me... knocking on midnight's door,
帰れないと泣いた
crying because I couldn't go home.
あの季節が 今目の前
That season is right before my eyes now.
stay with me... 口ぐせを言いながら
Stay with me... while saying our favorite phrases,
二人の時間を抱いて
embracing the moments we shared together,
まだ忘れず暖めてた
and still keeping them warm without forgetting.
stay with me... 真夜中のドアをたたき
Stay with me... knocking on midnight's door,
帰れないと泣いた
crying because I couldn't go home.
あの季節が 今目の前
That season is right before my eyes now.
stay with me...
波打ち際 ほぐれた髪 帽子 の先
Hair untied at the water's edge, past the tip of my hat
見覚えある 青いワーゲン Stop the Flashback
A familiar blue Volkswagen, stop the flashback
南風の いたずらな魔法ね
In southern winds, it's mischievous magic
遠い夏の あの眩暈に戻さないで Be with you Again
Don't take me back to that distant summer's vertigo, be with you again
Maybe Love, Stray My Heart
なにくわぬ顔をして
Putting on an innocent face
キスを奪って Don't Go Away
Stealing a kiss, don't go away
今だけは寄り添ってあげるわ
Only for now, I'll lean close to you
唇にぬくもり残して Close To You
Leaving warmth on your lips, close to you
肩すくめて ボンネットから腰上げて
Shrugging my shoulders, lifting my hips off the bonnet
喋りすぎよ 飽きてきたわ
Too much talking, I'm getting tired of it.
Stay the Flashlight
似た人みたい 解けかけた魔法ね
Like two similar people, a fading magic.
遠い夏の あの眩暈に戻りたいの
I want to return to the dizziness of that distant summer.
No more
Maybe Love, Stray My Heart
さりげないしぐさして
With a casual gesture,
キスをそらすわ I Go Away
I avert my kiss and go away.
夕立に付き合う気ないから
I have no mood to keep you company in a sudden shower.
崩れてくオンショア 波のまにまに
Crumbling onshore, at the mercy of the waves.
Turnaround
Maybe Love, Stray My Heart
何もかも 蜃気楼
Everything is a mirage.
夏の女神の 気まぐれね
It's just a whim of the summer goddess.
いつかまただなんて I Never Say
I never say "see you again sometime."
唇にうらはら 残したままで
Leaving contradictions lingering on my lips.
Turnaround
ガウルグラさん、そして宝鐘マリンさんによる新曲、よかったですねぇ。
Gawr Gura-san and Houshou Marine-san's new song was wonderful.
いや、よかったですねぇ。
Yeah, it really was.
いや、でも素晴らしかったです。
It was wonderful.
はい。
Yes.
えー、この後MVが公開されるそうなので、皆さんも楽しみにしていただければと思います。
The MV will be released after this, so I hope you look forward to it.
そうですね。
That's right.
はい。
Yes.
見させていただこうと思います。
We'll let you see it.
それにしても、ちょっと今回ポエムが多め、前、前ボームですか?
Even so, this time there are quite a few poems... Wait, a collection of poems?
そうなんです。
That's right.
いつかあのポエム集を出したいなと思っておりまして。
I've been thinking I want to release a poem collection sometime.
ポエム集を? へえー、なるほど。心のポエム集として。
A poem collection? I see, a collection of heart's poems.
ああ。お披露目しましょうか。
Ah. Shall we unveil it?
え、いいんですか? 今こんなアドリブで。
Eh, is that okay? Right now, with this ad-lib?
いけますよ、全然。
We can do it, absolutely.
おじょ、おじょおねがいします。
Then, um, please go ahead.
いやいいの、お嬢ちゃんで。
Yeah, Yochi-chan is fine.
ああ、お嬢の。
Ah, Yochi-chan.
では、行かせていただきます。
Then we'll let you go ahead.
白上フブキは狼宮と美味しい唐揚げを作る。
Shirakami Fubuki makes delicious karaage with Ookami Mio.
僕、僕...フォーエバー!
Me, me... Forever!
マリンちゃんちょっと待って!
Marine-chan, wait a second!
ポエムしちゃった!
You poemed!
本当だ、できちゃった!
You really poemed!
これやばいよ。
This is bad.
動きあやりやめろもう!
Stop that movement, stop it already!
宝生さん。
Houshou-san.
戻って戻って元に戻って!
Go back, go back, return to normal!
よかった目を覚ましてくれた。
Good thing you came to your senses.
何?
What?
いや、ちょっと二人とも今年もありがとうございました。
Well, thank you both for this year as well.
それはそれとして、ね、ちょっとこの後ライブしよう。
That being said, let's sing a live song after this.
え?
Eh?
さあ立って、おじっすってないで。
Stand up, don't be slouching.
おじっすってないで。
Don't be slouching.
ちょっと、ポエムはもういいだろ!
Come on, enough with the poems!
春一番が 掃除したてのサッシの窓に ほこりの渦を 踊らせてます
The first spring gale stirs up a swirl of dust in the freshly cleaned sash window.
机 本箱 運び出された荷物のあとは
After the desk and bookshelves and luggage were carried out,
畳の色が そこだけ若いわ
The tatami flooring looks so much newer only there.
お引っ越しのお祝い返しも済まないうちに
Before we've even finished thanking everyone for the moving gifts,
またですね
we're doing it again...
罠にかかった うさぎみたい
Like a rabbit caught in a trap,
イヤだわ あなた すすだらけ
Oh my, you're covered in soot all over.
おかしくって 涙が出そう
It's so funny, I feel like crying.
1 2 3 あの三叉路で
One, two, three, at that fork in the road,
軽く手を振り
giving a light wave goodbye,
私達 お別れなんですよ
we are finally parting ways.
タンスの陰で 心細めに迷子になった
Lost and feeling helpless behind the wardrobe,
ハートのエースが出てきましたよ
the ace of hearts has finally turned up.
おかしなものね 忘れた頃に見つかるなんて
Funny how things are found just when you forget them,
まるで青春の想い出そのもの
just like the memories of our youth itself.
お引っ越しのお祝い返しも 今度は二人
This time, the moving thank-you gifts are for the two of us,
別々ね
going separate ways...
何年たっても年下の人
Even after all these years, you're still younger than me.
イヤだわ シャツで顔拭いて
Oh dear, wiping your face with your shirt—
おかしくって 涙が出そう
it's so funny, I'm about to cry.
1 2 3 三つ数えて
One, two, three, counting to three,
見つめ合ったら 私達
looking into each other's eyes, we
お別れなんですね
are parting ways.
お引っ越しのお祝い返しは 微笑にして
I'll return the moving thanks with a smile,
届けます
and send it to you.
やさしい悪人と住み慣れた部屋
The cozy room lived in with a gentle devil—
それでは鍵が サカサマよ
now turn the key upside down.
おかしくって 涙が出そう
It's so funny, I feel like crying.
1 2 3 三歩目からは
One, two, three, from the third step onwards,
それぞれの道
each on our own path,
私達 歩いて行くんですね
we will walk away...
歩いて行くんですね
walking on our separate ways...
君たち昭和歌謡祭見てくださってどうもありがとう！
Thank you all so much for watching the Showa Kayou Festival!
宝鐘マリンの新曲「シンキロー」のリリースです！
It's the release of Houshou Marine's new song "Shinkiro"!
もう素晴らしすぎる楽曲とMVになってます！
It's an exceptionally wonderful song and music video!
このあとすぐ22時からプレミア公開となりますので
It will be premiering right after this at 22:00,
ぜひぜひぜひ絶対見てください！
so please, please, definitely check it out!
MVのストーリー今回はマリンが考えました！
Marine came up with the story for this music video!
詳しい制作裏話は振り返り配信でぜひ聞いてください！
Be sure to hear all about the behind-the-scenes in the recap stream!
そしてそして11月17日から23日にYouTube Shortsとのコラボレーションがあります！
And furthermore, from November 17th to the 23rd, there will be a YouTube Shorts collaboration!
さらに12月8日金曜日から12月10日日曜日には幕張メッセで開催される...
Plus, from Friday, December 8th to Sunday, December 10th, at Makuhari Messe...
まるで国境を超える新時代のカルチャー音楽フェス、
A cultural music festival of a new era transcending borders,
X-CONに船長が出演します！
Captain Marine will be performing at X-CON!
マリンは12月10日日曜日のX-CULTUREに出演します！
Marine will perform at X-CULTURE on Sunday, December 10th!
なんとこのそうそうたるメンツに混ぜていただきました！
I've been included among such an illustrious lineup!
生歌をいっぱい歌う予定なのでぜひ応援お願いします！
I plan on singing lots of live songs, so please support me!
雨にならないか不安なので君たち助けてくれ！
I'm worried it might rain, so guys, please help me out!
ちょっとしたサプライズもあるかもーんじゃい！
There might even be a little surprise!
え、ぜひ会場に足を運んできてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you could come to the venue!
現地チケットは発売中ですので詳しくはX-CONのホームページをご覧ください！
Tickets are on sale now, so check the X-CON homepage for details!
ではではグッズ販売のお知らせです！
Now then, here is an announcement about merchandise sales!
今回は推しアピールするのに使えるものを考えてみました！
This time, I thought of things you can use to show off your oshi!
まずはこちら、ビッグタオル！
First is this, the big towel!
これはバスタオルとして体を拭いたっていいし飾ったっていいし、
You can use it to dry off as a bath towel, or display it,
船長的には肩に引っかけてイベントに持って行って写真撮るときにバーンって広げて一味アピールしてほしいなと思って出しました！
and as for me, I hope you'll drape it over your shoulder at events and spread it wide when taking photos to show your Ichimi pride!
イラストはあかさあい先生！最高！
Illustrated by Akasa Ai sensei! The best!
続いてはこちら、トートバッグです！
Next is this, the tote bag!
さくさんがデザインしたもののマリンの部分だけ船長が描き下ろしました！
Out of Saku-san's design, only the Marine part was newly drawn by me!
ジュースっぽいデザインになっててドクロくんコップはクリアポケットになっています！
It has a juice-like design, and the Skull-kun cup is a clear pocket!
ぬいぐるみとか入れると透けてかわいい！
If you put a plushie or something inside, it shows through and is cute!
続いてはこちら、スマホグリップです！
Next is this, the smartphone grip!
マリンが描き下ろしました！
Newly drawn by Marine!
なんか飾っといてもいいしスマホに貼ってもいいし、何でも使い道あるよな！
You can display it or stick it on your phone, it has all sorts of uses!
そしてこちら、待望のクマリンぬいぐるみです！
And here, the long-awaited Kuma-Marine plushie!
三面状を船長が描きました！
Captain drew the three-view diagrams!
ふわふわした素材になっていて小さいのでぜひ持ち歩いてください！
It's made of fluffy material and it's small, so please carry it around!
全部セットでご購入いただきましたらば数量限定直筆メッセージ入りポストカードと面倒くさいマリンとお付き合いしている地獄ボイスがついてきます！
Purchasing the complete set includes a limited handwritten message postcard and a hellish voice where you date annoying Marine!
本当にめんどくさいので覚悟を決めて聞いてください！
It's really annoying, so make up your mind before listening!
マリンと付き合いたいならねこれくらいは耐えてください！
If you want to date Marine, you can endure at least this much!
数量限定がなくなった後もボイスはついてくるしポストカードには複製直筆メッセージ長文で入れますよ！
Even after the limited ones run out, the voice is included, and postcards get a long duplicated handwritten message!
というわけでこの後公開の新曲とメンバーシップ限定のミニライブも見てくださいね！
With that said, please also check out the new song released after this and the membership mini live!
それでは行きますよ！しゅっこうー！
Now then, here we go! Setting sail!